<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Monzo - Technology</title>
  <id>https://monzo.com/blog</id>
  <updated>2025-06-02T01:30:40Z</updated>
  <subtitle>An unofficial Monzo blog feed generated by Akash Goswami (https://akashgoswami.dev)</subtitle>
  <link href="https://monzo.com/blog"></link>
  <entry>
    <title>Designing bulk payments for how businesses really work</title>
    <updated>2025-05-28T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>tag:monzo.com,2025-05-28:/blog/designing-bulk-payments-for-how-businesses-really-work</id>
    <link href="https://monzo.com/blog/designing-bulk-payments-for-how-businesses-really-work" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">This blog discusses how we designed and built bulk payments: letting users send multiple payments in one go. It&#39;s a story of cross-team collaboration, complex challenges, and how we stayed laser-focused on what our users actually need to get done.</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Demystifying the Senior Staff+ Engineering interview process</title>
    <updated>2025-05-02T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>tag:monzo.com,2025-05-02:/blog/demystifying-the-senior-staff-engineering-interview-process</id>
    <link href="https://monzo.com/blog/demystifying-the-senior-staff-engineering-interview-process" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">We want to explain exactly what our Senior Staff+ interview process entails to make it fair and transparent for all our applicants. This post explains what you should expect from each of our interviewing stages and how to prepare.</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>How we built a product to demystify credit scores</title>
    <updated>2025-05-01T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>tag:monzo.com,2025-05-01:/blog/how-we-built-a-product-to-demystify-credit-scores</id>
    <link href="https://monzo.com/blog/how-we-built-a-product-to-demystify-credit-scores" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">This blogs explains the process of building and iterating on credit insights. We give you insight into how we use research to build products that meet customer needs, both at the start of the product design process and on an ongoing basis.</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Processing payments in Monzo Stand-in</title>
    <updated>2025-04-03T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>tag:monzo.com,2025-04-03:/blog/processing-payments-in-monzo-stand-in</id>
    <link href="https://monzo.com/blog/processing-payments-in-monzo-stand-in" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">Monzo Stand-in is able to process payments in the event of a major outage of the Primary Platform. Customers can continue to use their card and send or receive bank transfers as normal</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>We&#39;ve updated our engineering principles</title>
    <updated>2025-03-28T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>tag:monzo.com,2025-03-28:/blog/we-have-updated-our-engineering-principles</id>
    <link href="https://monzo.com/blog/we-have-updated-our-engineering-principles" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">At Monzo, we have a set of engineering principles which encapsulate what we value as an engineering organisation. We first wrote our engineering principles in 2018, and recently invested in updating them to better reflect where we are now</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Tolerating full cloud outages with Monzo Stand-in</title>
    <updated>2025-02-13T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>tag:monzo.com,2025-02-13:/blog/tolerating-full-cloud-outages-with-monzo-stand-in</id>
    <link href="https://monzo.com/blog/tolerating-full-cloud-outages-with-monzo-stand-in" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">We built a completely separate backup banking infrastructure called Monzo Stand-in to add another layer of defence so customers can continue to use important services provided by us</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Making identity verification more accessible </title>
    <updated>2025-02-06T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>tag:monzo.com,2025-02-06:/blog/making-identity-verification-more-accessible</id>
    <link href="https://monzo.com/blog/making-identity-verification-more-accessible" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">At Monzo we&#39;re trying to be an inclusive company that pushes boundaries in an attempt to reach our mission, to “Make money work for everyone”. We are taking steps to ensure everyone can us Monzo independently.</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Preparing for Mobile Interviews at Monzo</title>
    <updated>2025-01-29T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>tag:monzo.com,2025-01-29:/blog/preparing-for-mobile-interviews-at-monzo</id>
    <link href="https://monzo.com/blog/preparing-for-mobile-interviews-at-monzo" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">Our mobile interview process is designed to learn about your strengths. The post explains the specific skills and abilities that will make you successful in the role and what to expect in the interview process.</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>How each role in Borrowing Data allows us to think big and innovate</title>
    <updated>2025-01-16T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>tag:monzo.com,2025-01-16:/blog/how-each-role-in-borrowing-data-allows-us-to-think-big-and-innovate</id>
    <link href="https://monzo.com/blog/how-each-role-in-borrowing-data-allows-us-to-think-big-and-innovate" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">Monzo has a huge variety of data roles in our Borrowing team that contribute to developing our credit products. In this blog we tell you what Borrowing at Monzo is, how it fits into Monzo, what the types of roles we hire for, and how to apply.</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Don&#39;t let go of your creative spark</title>
    <updated>2024-12-13T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>tag:monzo.com,2024-12-13:/blog/dont-let-go-of-your-creative-spark</id>
    <link href="https://monzo.com/blog/dont-let-go-of-your-creative-spark" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">Our Product Designer, Victoria, talks about her learnings from the course &#39;100 Design Projects&#39; she attended this year, including sprinkling your own personality in every project and making sure you reflect on your own creative process.</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>How our design team shapes products for our customers</title>
    <updated>2024-11-21T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>tag:monzo.com,2024-11-21:/blog/how-our-design-team-shapes-products-for-our-customers</id>
    <link href="https://monzo.com/blog/how-our-design-team-shapes-products-for-our-customers" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">This blog explains why design and research is so impactful at Monzo. We explain how we give designers and researchers an abundance of autonomy to help make decisions, and why it makes our team an outlier for those who care about making a difference.</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Inclusive Hiring in Engineering at Monzo</title>
    <updated>2024-11-07T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>tag:monzo.com,2024-11-07:/blog/inclusive-hiring-in-engineering-at-monzo</id>
    <link href="https://monzo.com/blog/inclusive-hiring-in-engineering-at-monzo" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">Monzo cares about inclusive hiring in engineering by doing things like advertising our salaries on our job ads, sharing our process transparently, and providing different options for doing different technical interview stages</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Vertically scaling ordered consumption using Kafka</title>
    <updated>2024-10-29T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>tag:monzo.com,2024-10-29:/blog/vertically-scaling-ordered-consumption-using-kafka</id>
    <link href="https://monzo.com/blog/vertically-scaling-ordered-consumption-using-kafka" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">We built our “unordered concurrent” subscription knowing that we could eventually extend it to support ordering in Kafka</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Demystifying the Backend Engineering interview process</title>
    <updated>2024-09-30T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>tag:monzo.com,2024-09-30:/blog/demystifying-the-backend-engineering-interview-process</id>
    <link href="https://monzo.com/blog/demystifying-the-backend-engineering-interview-process" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">We want to explain exactly what our Backend Engineering interview process entails to make it fair and transparent for all our applicants. This post explains what you should expect from each of our interviewing stages and how to prepare.</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Enabling horizontal autoscaling with co-operative distributed rate limiting</title>
    <updated>2024-09-30T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>tag:monzo.com,2024-09-30:/blog/enabling-horizontal-autoscaling-with-co-operative-distributed-rate-limiting</id>
    <link href="https://monzo.com/blog/enabling-horizontal-autoscaling-with-co-operative-distributed-rate-limiting" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">Monzo runs almost 3,000 microservices to power everything. A core part of being able to run all these systems and features safely is rate limiting. In this blog post we describe how that gets us to doing what we call “distributed rate limiting.”</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>We built a better system for scheduling cron jobs</title>
    <updated>2024-09-18T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>tag:monzo.com,2024-09-18:/blog/we-built-a-better-system-for-scheduling-cron-jobs</id>
    <link href="https://monzo.com/blog/we-built-a-better-system-for-scheduling-cron-jobs" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">We built a system to define scheduled jobs that moves away from cron and adds support for timezones, better monitoring and a more delightful developer experience</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>How we cut time to sign up for Monzo US from 17 minutes to 4 minutes</title>
    <updated>2024-09-04T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>tag:monzo.com,2024-09-04:/blog/how-we-cut-time-to-sign-up-for-monzo-us-from-17-minutes-to-4-minutes</id>
    <link href="https://monzo.com/blog/how-we-cut-time-to-sign-up-for-monzo-us-from-17-minutes-to-4-minutes" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">This blog talks about how our Monzo US team revamped the signup process for customers by experimenting with signup funnel improvements, increasing the rate of completion by a massive 400%</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>How we run migrations across 2,800 microservices</title>
    <updated>2024-08-26T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>tag:monzo.com,2024-08-26:/blog/how-we-run-migrations-across-2800-microservices</id>
    <link href="https://monzo.com/blog/how-we-run-migrations-across-2800-microservices" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">We&#39;ve got a lot of value from our microservices architecture (2,800 and counting!), but this architecture is not without its challenges. One of those challenges is how to make sweeping library changes across all those services.</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Building a processing system for International Payments</title>
    <updated>2024-07-31T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>tag:monzo.com,2024-07-31:/blog/building-a-processing-system-for-international-payments</id>
    <link href="https://monzo.com/blog/building-a-processing-system-for-international-payments" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">Gain an understanding of how International Payments are sent and received and how we process them at Monzo. We are making this seamless to customers whilst also having a strong focus on development experience</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>The ultimate guide on using AI to ace an interview at Monzo</title>
    <updated>2024-07-30T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>tag:monzo.com,2024-07-30:/blog/the-ultimate-guide-on-using-ai-to-ace-an-interview-at-monzo</id>
    <link href="https://monzo.com/blog/the-ultimate-guide-on-using-ai-to-ace-an-interview-at-monzo" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">We think there are lots of benefits associated with AI, but we have a human approach to hiring. At every stage there is a person reviewing and making decisions to ensure we&#39;re able to bring the best people to Monzo.</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>How we securely generate sensitive secrets</title>
    <updated>2024-07-22T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>tag:monzo.com,2024-07-22:/blog/how-we-securely-generate-sensitive-secrets</id>
    <link href="https://monzo.com/blog/how-we-securely-generate-sensitive-secrets" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">We regularly have to create and manage secrets that grant very sensitive privileges, and so we&#39;ve created a new process that makes it fast and easy for us to securely and verifiably perform all kinds of sensitive operations.</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Making mortgages more Monzo</title>
    <updated>2024-07-19T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>tag:monzo.com,2024-07-19:/blog/making-mortgages-more-monzo</id>
    <link href="https://monzo.com/blog/making-mortgages-more-monzo" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">This blog talks about how we went 0-1 with our new Homeownership mortgage feature. It gives insight into how we transitioned from a mortgage-focused to a home-focused view, where equity (customer&#39;s progress) sits at the heart of the experience.</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Delightful Payments</title>
    <updated>2024-07-03T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>tag:monzo.com,2024-07-03:/blog/delightful-payments/</id>
    <link href="https://monzo.com/blog/delightful-payments/" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">This post is about how we built the Delightful Payments which directly replaced our P2P (Monzo-to-Monzo) and FPS (bank transfers) payment flows, including how we iterated on product in-parallel with design, and continuous feedback cycles.</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Securing our software supply-chain better with reproducible builds for enclaves</title>
    <updated>2024-06-20T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>tag:monzo.com,2024-06-20:/blog/securing-our-software-supply-chain-better-with-reproducible-builds-for</id>
    <link href="https://monzo.com/blog/securing-our-software-supply-chain-better-with-reproducible-builds-for" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">This blog talks about how we protect our workloads against supply chain attacks, specifically by achieving bit-by-bit reproducible builds, and how we have adopted Nix an alternative to Docker for build environments.</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>How we use incremental modelling to handle billions of events every day</title>
    <updated>2024-05-29T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>tag:monzo.com,2024-05-29:/blog/how-we-use-incremental-modelling-to-handle-billions-of-events-every-day</id>
    <link href="https://monzo.com/blog/how-we-use-incremental-modelling-to-handle-billions-of-events-every-day" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">This post is an overview of how we leverage incremental modelling, a data transformation technique which helps us scale sustainably as we blast off to 10 million customers 🚀</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>How we measured change aversion with our new home screen</title>
    <updated>2024-04-26T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>tag:monzo.com,2024-04-26:/blog/how-we-measured-change-aversion-with-our-new-home-screen</id>
    <link href="https://monzo.com/blog/how-we-measured-change-aversion-with-our-new-home-screen" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">When we launched our new Monzo home screen, Katherine spent the past year focused on designing, launching and analysing experiments to understand how customers reacted to their new app. This blog explains how she measured change aversion.</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>User Research Insight to Impact: The Art of Scaling Impact and Crafting Goal-Driven Metrics </title>
    <updated>2024-03-15T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>tag:monzo.com,2024-03-15:/blog/user-research-insight-to-impact-the-art-of-scaling-impact-and-crafting-goal</id>
    <link href="https://monzo.com/blog/user-research-insight-to-impact-the-art-of-scaling-impact-and-crafting-goal" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">Drawing upon the wisdom and practices of our user research team at Monzo, this blog post captures ways to scale user research impact, craft effective goals, and define clear metrics.</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Starting from scratch as a new engineer at Monzo</title>
    <updated>2024-03-08T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>tag:monzo.com,2024-03-08:/blog/starting-from-scratch-as-a-new-engineer-at-monzo</id>
    <link href="https://monzo.com/blog/starting-from-scratch-as-a-new-engineer-at-monzo" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">I&#39;m Grace, and I joined Monzo in October &#39;23 as a Backend Engineer in Fincrime Business Banking. I&#39;m here to convince you to apply for that role you really want, and about how exciting, challenging and rewarding changing roles has been for me.</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Moving monzo.com</title>
    <updated>2024-03-01T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>tag:monzo.com,2024-03-01:/blog/moving-monzo-com</id>
    <link href="https://monzo.com/blog/moving-monzo-com" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">In 2022, we embarked on a long journey to move our main website. The whole process took us from June of 2022 to November of 2023, with plenty of fun curveballs along the way. Let&#39;s dig into what it takes to migrate monzo.com.</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>How we use design to create business impact</title>
    <updated>2024-02-22T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>tag:monzo.com,2024-02-22:/blog/how-we-use-design-to-create-business-impact-at-monzo</id>
    <link href="https://monzo.com/blog/how-we-use-design-to-create-business-impact-at-monzo" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">This post delves into how Monzo is building on our product-led growth by adopting new growth design ways of working and how uniquely positioned design is as a business tool for growth. Buckle-up!</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>What are Monzo&#39;s technical expectations for Engineering Leaders? </title>
    <updated>2024-02-19T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>tag:monzo.com,2024-02-19:/blog/what-are-monzos-technical-expectations-for-engineering-leaders</id>
    <link href="https://monzo.com/blog/what-are-monzos-technical-expectations-for-engineering-leaders" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">This post will explore how EMs at Monzo continue to leverage their software engineering backgrounds in practice, and how Monzo assesses those skills in our hiring process.</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>How to create a customer segmentation: choosing the right segmentation approach</title>
    <updated>2024-02-15T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>tag:monzo.com,2024-02-15:/blog/how-to-create-a-customer-segmentation-choosing-the-right-segmentation</id>
    <link href="https://monzo.com/blog/how-to-create-a-customer-segmentation-choosing-the-right-segmentation" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">Customer segmentation is the art of dividing customers into useful groups, but there are a lot of pitfalls to avoid along the way. Here is Monzo&#39;s guide to help you decide your segmentation approach, collect the right data, and more.</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>How we built a queue on top of Kafka </title>
    <updated>2024-01-25T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>tag:monzo.com,2024-01-25:/blog/how-we-built-a-queue-on-top-of-kafka</id>
    <link href="https://monzo.com/blog/how-we-built-a-queue-on-top-of-kafka" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">This blog covers core parts of the journey Constantijn embarked on when he raised his first &#34;small change&#34; pull request, and how over time we have built a rich client library and set of abstractions that sit on top of Kafka</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>How we unified our customers&#39; activity on the new home screen</title>
    <updated>2024-01-10T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>tag:monzo.com,2024-01-10:/blog/how-we-unified-our-customers-activity-on-the-new-home-screen</id>
    <link href="https://monzo.com/blog/how-we-unified-our-customers-activity-on-the-new-home-screen" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">In this blog post, we explore how we built our home screen, a single stream of activity that lets you glance over the latest updates across all your bank accounts! Less searching around, less app-hopping, less confusion. </summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Building Year in Monzo - as told by engineering</title>
    <updated>2023-12-22T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>tag:monzo.com,2023-12-22:/blog/building-year-in-monzo-as-told-by-engineering</id>
    <link href="https://monzo.com/blog/building-year-in-monzo-as-told-by-engineering" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">We&#39;ve shared the behind the scenes insights into how we wrote 5 million Years in Monzo, and the magic behind the data. Now we&#39;re going to dig into how we turned this data into the Year in Monzo experience you know and love.</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Securing admin access to Monzo&#39;s platform</title>
    <updated>2023-12-15T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>tag:monzo.com,2023-12-15:/blog/2023/12/14/securing-admin-access-to-monzos-platform/</id>
    <link href="https://monzo.com/blog/2023/12/14/securing-admin-access-to-monzos-platform/" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">Monzo runs on a shared platform of infrastructure that hosts our microservices. In this post, we&#39;ll discuss how we broker access to our infrastructure credentials with a system that is resistant to attacks even from the team that maintains it.</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>A Day in the Life of a Technical Programme Manager at Monzo</title>
    <updated>2023-11-24T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>tag:monzo.com,2023-11-24:/blog/2023/11/24/a-day-in-the-life-of-a-technical-programme-manager-at-monzo</id>
    <link href="https://monzo.com/blog/2023/11/24/a-day-in-the-life-of-a-technical-programme-manager-at-monzo" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">The Technical Programme Manager (TPM for short) role is hugely varied. I want to take you on a journey through a typical day in my life as a Technical Programme Manager here at Monzo.</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Protecting our platform from spikes in usage by reducing load from the Monzo app</title>
    <updated>2023-10-12T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>tag:monzo.com,2023-10-12:/blog/2023/10/12/protecting-our-platform-from-spikes-in-usage-by-reducing-load-from-the-monzo</id>
    <link href="https://monzo.com/blog/2023/10/12/protecting-our-platform-from-spikes-in-usage-by-reducing-load-from-the-monzo" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">This blog explores how we&#39;ve made our platform more resilient to spikes in app opens. We can now reduce load on our platform before we get overwhelmed so you can still access and use critical parts of the app, and your card continues to work.</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>The SKAdNetwork Puzzle: Using Data to Solve for Effective Performance Marketing</title>
    <updated>2023-09-12T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>tag:monzo.com,2023-09-12:/blog/2023/09/12/the-skadnetwork-puzzle-using-data-to-solve-for-effective-performance/</id>
    <link href="https://monzo.com/blog/2023/09/12/the-skadnetwork-puzzle-using-data-to-solve-for-effective-performance/" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">This blog talks through how Monzo uses Data Science and Analytics Engineering to measure the value of paid marketing as Apple&#39;s SKAdNetwork changes the mobile advertising landscape, which helps to inform our wider strategies of sustainable growth</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Tech leading as a mobile engineer at Monzo</title>
    <updated>2023-08-31T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>tag:monzo.com,2023-08-31:/blog/2023/08/23/tech-leading-as-a-mobile-engineer-at-monzo</id>
    <link href="https://monzo.com/blog/2023/08/23/tech-leading-as-a-mobile-engineer-at-monzo" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">Mark has written about his experience and growth as a tech lead at Monzo over the last 18 months - from creeping doubts to using his mobile engineer&#39;s perspective to shape the role to his strengths</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>My path from Intern to Staff Engineer at Monzo</title>
    <updated>2023-08-10T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>tag:monzo.com,2023-08-10:/blog/2023/08/10/my-path-from-intern-to-staff-engineer-at-monzo</id>
    <link href="https://monzo.com/blog/2023/08/10/my-path-from-intern-to-staff-engineer-at-monzo" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">This blog discusses our Staff Engineer, Jacob, and his experience starting at Monzo as an intern in Engineering, and how he has developed into a Staff Engineer role.</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>How we launch new products at Monzo</title>
    <updated>2023-08-03T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>tag:monzo.com,2023-08-03:/blog/2023/08/03/how-we-launch-new-products-at-monzo</id>
    <link href="https://monzo.com/blog/2023/08/03/how-we-launch-new-products-at-monzo" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">From staff testing to Monzo Labs, learn about the different ways Monzo launches new products and features - and how we don&#39;t always get it right!</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Five lessons from my first year at Monzo</title>
    <updated>2023-07-18T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>tag:monzo.com,2023-07-18:/blog/2023/07/18/five-lessons-from-my-first-year-at-monzo</id>
    <link href="https://monzo.com/blog/2023/07/18/five-lessons-from-my-first-year-at-monzo" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">Tarah Srethwatanakul is a Lead Researcher at Monzo. In this blog post, she shares lessons from her first year at the company.</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>How we do product management in the financial difficulties space</title>
    <updated>2023-07-12T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>tag:monzo.com,2023-07-12:/blog/2023/07/10/how-we-do-product-management-in-the-financial-difficulties-space</id>
    <link href="https://monzo.com/blog/2023/07/10/how-we-do-product-management-in-the-financial-difficulties-space" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">In Financial Health, we&#39;re responsible for making sure we build the right tools and experiences to help our customers through thick and thin if they experience financial difficulties, while also helping Monzo grow its Borrowing products.</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Finding your fit in a new product team </title>
    <updated>2023-06-01T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>tag:monzo.com,2023-06-01:/blog/2023/06/01/finding-your-fit-in-a-new-product-team/</id>
    <link href="https://monzo.com/blog/2023/06/01/finding-your-fit-in-a-new-product-team/" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">This is my experience of how I searched for and found my fit as a Product Designer in my first few months at Monzo, but I believe this applies to any role joining a new product team.</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Sensitivity analysis</title>
    <updated>2023-05-18T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>tag:monzo.com,2023-05-18:/blog/2023/05/18/sensitivity-analysis</id>
    <link href="https://monzo.com/blog/2023/05/18/sensitivity-analysis" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">This blog explains sensitivity analysis, which is a useful data science technique for assessing the impact of different variables on an outcome metric.</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>How we manage technology risk at Monzo </title>
    <updated>2023-05-10T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>tag:monzo.com,2023-05-10:/blog/2023/05/04/how-we-manage-technology-risk-at-monzo</id>
    <link href="https://monzo.com/blog/2023/05/04/how-we-manage-technology-risk-at-monzo" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">In this post, three Monzonauts explain how they work together with each other and other disciplines to manage risk in a fast-moving tech-focused banking environment. </summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Speeding up our balance read time: The planning phase</title>
    <updated>2023-04-28T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>tag:monzo.com,2023-04-28:/blog/2023/04/28/speeding-up-our-balance-read-time-the-planning-phase</id>
    <link href="https://monzo.com/blog/2023/04/28/speeding-up-our-balance-read-time-the-planning-phase" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">The ledger is where we keep track of all customer money movements coming in and out of customers&#39; accounts. We started a project to speed up the ledger balance read time. In this post we&#39;ll cover the planning and experiments we ran.</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>What we learned from 43 experiments in 12 months</title>
    <updated>2023-03-28T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>tag:monzo.com,2023-03-28:/blog/2023/03/28/what-we-learned-from-43-experiments-in-12-months</id>
    <link href="https://monzo.com/blog/2023/03/28/what-we-learned-from-43-experiments-in-12-months" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">This blog shares some of the learnings we&#39;ve had from our experiments in customer help and support over the last year</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Sweating the Small Stuff: What do app screens and pedestrian-crossings have in common? </title>
    <updated>2023-03-20T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>tag:monzo.com,2023-03-20:/blog/2023/03/20/what-do-app-screens-and-pedestrian-crossings-have-in-common</id>
    <link href="https://monzo.com/blog/2023/03/20/what-do-app-screens-and-pedestrian-crossings-have-in-common" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">This blog talks about why app screens are like pedestrian crossings, or more specifically, how some subtle tweaks to a user-interface in Monzo&#39;s sign-up process has had a surprisingly large impact!</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Designing a regional experiment to measure incrementality</title>
    <updated>2023-03-02T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>tag:monzo.com,2023-03-02:/blog/2022/03/02/designing-a-regional-experiment-to-measure-incrementality</id>
    <link href="https://monzo.com/blog/2022/03/02/designing-a-regional-experiment-to-measure-incrementality" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">This blog post covers the approach for how we designed a regional experiment to measure the incremental impact of our referral scheme on new customer growth.</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Becoming direct participants of Bacs</title>
    <updated>2023-02-22T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>tag:monzo.com,2023-02-22:/blog/2023/02/22/becoming-direct-participants-of-bacs</id>
    <link href="https://monzo.com/blog/2023/02/22/becoming-direct-participants-of-bacs" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">In September 2022, Monzo became a Direct Participant of the Bacs scheme. In this post, Tech Lead Ryan explains how we built a new connection to the the Bacs scheme over the SWIFT banking network and managed the risks involved.</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>How we prepare for huge spikes in traffic as millions of our customers get paid early</title>
    <updated>2023-01-27T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>tag:monzo.com,2023-01-27:/blog/2023/01/26/preparing-for-spikes-in-traffic-as-millions-get-paid-early</id>
    <link href="https://monzo.com/blog/2023/01/26/preparing-for-spikes-in-traffic-as-millions-get-paid-early" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">This blog explains the problems that occur when hundreds of thousands of customers all request to be paid millions of pounds at almost exactly the same time, and what we do to keep things running smoothly while that happens.</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Machine Learning at Monzo in 2022</title>
    <updated>2022-12-19T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>tag:monzo.com,2022-12-19:/blog/2022/12/19/machine-learning-at-monzo-in-2022</id>
    <link href="https://monzo.com/blog/2022/12/19/machine-learning-at-monzo-in-2022" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">An end-of-year review of how machine learning continues to evolve and grow at Monzo</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Building an extension framework for dbt </title>
    <updated>2022-12-15T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>tag:monzo.com,2022-12-15:/blog/2022/12/15/building-an-extension-framework-for-dbt</id>
    <link href="https://monzo.com/blog/2022/12/15/building-an-extension-framework-for-dbt" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">dbt is a fundamental piece of Monzo&#39;s data platform. We made the big decision to build a whole new extension framework that would give us more flexibility.</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Monzo Magic hackathon: 3 days, 120 ideas, 333 Monzonauts</title>
    <updated>2022-12-13T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>tag:monzo.com,2022-12-13:/blog/2022/12/13/monzo-magic-hackathon</id>
    <link href="https://monzo.com/blog/2022/12/13/monzo-magic-hackathon" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">This August, as we were wrapping up the summer, Monzonauts across the business set out to learn from each other, have fun and build things centred around one theme: Monzo Magic. This activity is commonly referred to in the industry as a hackathon.</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Reducing our NAT Gateway cost with private networking between AWS and GCP</title>
    <updated>2022-11-25T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>tag:monzo.com,2022-11-25:/blog/2022/11/25/reducing-nat-gateway-cost-with-private-networking-between-aws-and-gcp</id>
    <link href="https://monzo.com/blog/2022/11/25/reducing-nat-gateway-cost-with-private-networking-between-aws-and-gcp" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">Sharing knowledge on how we implementing private networking between AWS and GCP</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>How insights shaped building a 0-1 product: Monzo Flex</title>
    <updated>2022-11-18T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>tag:monzo.com,2022-11-18:/blog/2022/11/16/how-insights-shaped-building-a-0-1-product-monzo-flex</id>
    <link href="https://monzo.com/blog/2022/11/16/how-insights-shaped-building-a-0-1-product-monzo-flex" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">We wanted to share more about why we launched a new 0-1 product to help people pay for purchases later and how a mixed-method research discovery led to the product that over hundreds of thousands of customers use and love today!</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Taking a design system approach to research guidelines</title>
    <updated>2022-11-10T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>tag:monzo.com,2022-11-10:/blog/2022/11/10/design-system-approach-to-research-guidelines</id>
    <link href="https://monzo.com/blog/2022/11/10/design-system-approach-to-research-guidelines" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">If you&#39;re starting out in a new role in research ops, design ops or any other kind of team operations, this blog will take you through the ins and outs of creating a flexible how-to guide database for scale.</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Argo Rollouts at scale: Bringing Automated Rollbacks to 2,100+ services at Monzo</title>
    <updated>2022-11-07T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>tag:monzo.com,2022-11-07:/blog/2022/11/02/argo-rollouts-at-scale</id>
    <link href="https://monzo.com/blog/2022/11/02/argo-rollouts-at-scale" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">We introduced automated rollbacks to our platform using Argo Rollouts and made it the default deployment strategy for all our services. This helps us roll out changes safely and catch a wide class of problems related to deploying new code</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Migrating our monorepo seamlessly from Dep to Go Modules</title>
    <updated>2022-09-28T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>tag:monzo.com,2022-09-28:/blog/2022/09/29/migrating-our-monorepo-seamlessly-from-dep-to-go-modules</id>
    <link href="https://monzo.com/blog/2022/09/29/migrating-our-monorepo-seamlessly-from-dep-to-go-modules" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">Since 2018, we&#39;ve used Dep to manage our monorepo dependencies, but when it was deprecated switching to Go Modules was a high risk change. This post explains how we reduced that risk by iteratively updating our dependencies for a seamless migration.</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Scaling our security detection pipeline with Sigma</title>
    <updated>2022-08-04T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>tag:monzo.com,2022-08-04:/blog/2022/08/05/scaling-our-security-detection-pipeline-with-sigma</id>
    <link href="https://monzo.com/blog/2022/08/05/scaling-our-security-detection-pipeline-with-sigma" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">Detective controls help us monitor our systems for unwanted behaviour, but since writing our first detection rules, our company and team has grown. This post explains how we scaled those detection rules using Sigma and have open sourced our tooling.</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Switching from Customer Service Representative to Backend Engineer</title>
    <updated>2022-07-25T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>tag:monzo.com,2022-07-25:/blog/2022/07/26/switching-from-customer-service-representative-to-backend-engineer</id>
    <link href="https://monzo.com/blog/2022/07/26/switching-from-customer-service-representative-to-backend-engineer" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">Kyle joined Monzo as a COp, a customer service representative, but three years on he now works in a product team as one of our backend engineers! Kyle and his mentor Duncan share the story of how Kyle made his career switch</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Redefining our microservice development process</title>
    <updated>2022-06-23T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>tag:monzo.com,2022-06-23:/blog/2022/06/24/redefining-our-microservice-development-process</id>
    <link href="https://monzo.com/blog/2022/06/24/redefining-our-microservice-development-process" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">We&#39;ve been working on some new techniques to help make the development of services easier as we continue to grow and the entire platform can&#39;t be run locally.</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Our mobile release process: An illustrated story</title>
    <updated>2022-06-22T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>tag:monzo.com,2022-06-22:/blog/2022/06/23/our-mobile-release-process-an-illustrated-story</id>
    <link href="https://monzo.com/blog/2022/06/23/our-mobile-release-process-an-illustrated-story" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">We go into our mobile release process and how we&#39;re able to sustain a steady stream of releases as the changes that go into each version increase over time</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Humans who can RPC: securing staff access to 2000 microservices</title>
    <updated>2022-05-25T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>tag:monzo.com,2022-05-25:/blog/2022/05/26/humans-who-can-rpc-securing-staff-access-to-microservices</id>
    <link href="https://monzo.com/blog/2022/05/26/humans-who-can-rpc-securing-staff-access-to-microservices" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">With over 2000 microservices and lots of Remote Procedure Calls (RPCs) that are constantly changing, we needed a new way to manage staff access. The Security Platform team explain how we now define RPC permissions directly in proto files.</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Joining Monzo as a Data Scientist</title>
    <updated>2022-05-17T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>tag:monzo.com,2022-05-17:/blog/2022/05/18/joining-monzo-as-a-data-scientist</id>
    <link href="https://monzo.com/blog/2022/05/18/joining-monzo-as-a-data-scientist" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">Izak joined Monzo as a data scientist in February. In this post, he shares his journey to Monzo and his early experience in the data discipline, with our data stack, and in the team looking after our Customer Operations.</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>How we deploy to production over 100 times a day</title>
    <updated>2022-05-15T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>tag:monzo.com,2022-05-15:/blog/2022/05/16/how-we-deploy-to-production-over-100-times-a-day</id>
    <link href="https://monzo.com/blog/2022/05/16/how-we-deploy-to-production-over-100-times-a-day" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">Our success relies on us rapidly shipping new features. To achieve this rapid release cadence, we&#39;ve optimised our engineering culture, tooling, and architecture to go from idea to production as frictionless as possible, without sacrificing safety.</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Becoming an Engineering Manager: 1 year in</title>
    <updated>2022-05-05T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>tag:monzo.com,2022-05-05:/blog/2022/05/06/becoming-an-engineering-manager-1-year-in</id>
    <link href="https://monzo.com/blog/2022/05/06/becoming-an-engineering-manager-1-year-in" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">Last year, I made the switch into engineering management full time. It&#39;s been an interesting journey with lots of lessons learned.</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>How our Android engineers automated the removal of Kotlin synthetics</title>
    <updated>2022-04-20T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>tag:monzo.com,2022-04-20:/blog/2022/04/20/how-our-android-engineers-automated-the-removal-of-kotlin-synthetics</id>
    <link href="https://monzo.com/blog/2022/04/20/how-our-android-engineers-automated-the-removal-of-kotlin-synthetics" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">Our Mobile Platform team recently faced the challenge of having to remove all synthetic view properties. This post explains how we built a tool to automate the task and the trade-offs we had to consider along the way.</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>How everyone at Monzo gets involved with testing</title>
    <updated>2022-04-11T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>tag:monzo.com,2022-04-11:/blog/2022/04/12/how-anyone-at-monzo-can-test</id>
    <link href="https://monzo.com/blog/2022/04/12/how-anyone-at-monzo-can-test" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">Everyone at Monzo gets involved in testing new features and versions of the app before we release them. In this post Sarah, part of our Quality Assurance team, explains the different types of tests we use and how we run them.</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>My first 3 months at Monzo as an engineering manager</title>
    <updated>2022-04-03T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>tag:monzo.com,2022-04-03:/blog/2022/04/04/my-first-3-months-at-monzo-as-an-engineering-manager</id>
    <link href="https://monzo.com/blog/2022/04/04/my-first-3-months-at-monzo-as-an-engineering-manager" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">Jarryd joined Monzo as an engineering manager a few months ago. In this post he shares his journey to Monzo and how he found his feet in his new role.</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>How we secure Monzo&#39;s banking platform</title>
    <updated>2022-03-30T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>tag:monzo.com,2022-03-30:/blog/2022/03/31/how-we-secure-monzos-banking-platform</id>
    <link href="https://monzo.com/blog/2022/03/31/how-we-secure-monzos-banking-platform" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">Our Security Infrastructure team introduces the principles we follow to build security in Monzo&#39;s fast-moving engineering environment and how they work with other engineering teams to keep our customers and platform safe.</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Data hiring at Monzo: The interview process</title>
    <updated>2022-03-21T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>tag:monzo.com,2022-03-21:/blog/2022/03/21/data-hiring-at-monzo</id>
    <link href="https://monzo.com/blog/2022/03/21/data-hiring-at-monzo" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">We hire lots of different people in Data who join us to work in a lot of different teams. Our interviews are designed to do two things: teach you about Monzo and capture information that tells us the role is right for you.</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Scaling our on-call process</title>
    <updated>2022-02-24T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>tag:monzo.com,2022-02-24:/blog/2022-02-24/scaling-our-on-call-process</id>
    <link href="https://monzo.com/blog/2022-02-24/scaling-our-on-call-process" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">As Monzo has grown, we&#39;ve continued to change our on-call process so we can keep our systems running smoothly without sacrificing the wellbeing of our engineers. Luke Briscoe explains what we&#39;ve changed and how.</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>How we calculate balances</title>
    <updated>2022-02-18T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>tag:monzo.com,2022-02-18:/blog/2022/02/18/how-we-calculate-balances</id>
    <link href="https://monzo.com/blog/2022/02/18/how-we-calculate-balances" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">In June 2021 we started designing and implementing a new way to calculate balances that is more reliable and consistent. This post explains why the old approach needed improving and the changes we made.</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Securely delegating trust with digital signatures and secret storage systems</title>
    <updated>2022-02-15T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>tag:monzo.com,2022-02-15:/blog/2022/02/15/securely-delegating-trust-with-digital-signatures-and-secret-storage-systems</id>
    <link href="https://monzo.com/blog/2022/02/15/securely-delegating-trust-with-digital-signatures-and-secret-storage-systems" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">This post explains how our public key infrastructure uses a combination of different secret storage systems to implement a balance between security assurances and usability.</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Processing payments safely at scale</title>
    <updated>2022-02-08T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>tag:monzo.com,2022-02-08:/blog/2022/02/08/processing-payments-safely-at-scale</id>
    <link href="https://monzo.com/blog/2022/02/08/processing-payments-safely-at-scale" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">We ship changes many times a day while making sure that payments are processed as expected. This blog post explores how we do this and focuses on two ideas that could be useful outside of the world of payment processing.</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>How we validated our handling time data</title>
    <updated>2022-02-04T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>tag:monzo.com,2022-02-04:/blog/2022/02/04/how-we-validated-our-handling-time-data</id>
    <link href="https://monzo.com/blog/2022/02/04/how-we-validated-our-handling-time-data" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">We make lots of decisions based on data from customer support. We need to make sure we can trust this data. In this post, Niamh explains how her team validated the data.</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Keep your phone and Monzo app up to date</title>
    <updated>2022-01-28T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>tag:monzo.com,2022-01-28:/blog/2022/01/28/keep-your-phone-and-monzo-app-up-to-date</id>
    <link href="https://monzo.com/blog/2022/01/28/keep-your-phone-and-monzo-app-up-to-date" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">Your Monzo account is more secure and you have access to all our latest features when your app and phone are up to date.</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>My first 6 months at Monzo as a Backend Engineer</title>
    <updated>2022-01-17T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>tag:monzo.com,2022-01-17:/blog/2022/02/17/my-first-6-months-at-monzo-as-a-backend-engineer</id>
    <link href="https://monzo.com/blog/2022/02/17/my-first-6-months-at-monzo-as-a-backend-engineer" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">Bee Skerritt joined the Infrastructure squad as a backend engineer. In this post, he explains his journey to Monzo and his experience so far.</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>How we protect our most sensitive secrets from the most determined attackers</title>
    <updated>2021-11-18T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>tag:monzo.com,2021-11-18:/blog/2021/11/18/protecting-our-most-sensitive-secrets</id>
    <link href="https://monzo.com/blog/2021/11/18/protecting-our-most-sensitive-secrets" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">As a bank, we have private keys and other &#39;secrets&#39; we need to protect, to keep our customers and ourselves safe. Our security controls work together to stop even the most determined and capable attackers.</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>An introduction to Monzo&#39;s data stack</title>
    <updated>2021-10-13T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>tag:monzo.com,2021-10-13:/blog/2021/10/14/an-introduction-to-monzos-data-stack</id>
    <link href="https://monzo.com/blog/2021/10/14/an-introduction-to-monzos-data-stack" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">An overview of the data stack we use at Monzo, some of the challenges we face, and what we want to change.</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Documenting pull requests is as important as writing good code</title>
    <updated>2021-09-30T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>tag:monzo.com,2021-09-30:/blog/2021/09/30/documenting-pull-requests-is-as-important-as-writing-good-code</id>
    <link href="https://monzo.com/blog/2021/09/30/documenting-pull-requests-is-as-important-as-writing-good-code" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">How our engineering teams document pull requests to help other teams and their future colleagues review changes.</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>How we&#39;ve started to measure &#39;software excellence&#39; </title>
    <updated>2021-09-15T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>tag:monzo.com,2021-09-15:/blog/2021/09/15/how-we-measure-software-excellence</id>
    <link href="https://monzo.com/blog/2021/09/15/how-we-measure-software-excellence" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">We&#39;re experimenting with ways to measure, track, and improve the quality of our software.</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Lessons from implementing engineering progression frameworks at scale</title>
    <updated>2021-04-22T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>tag:monzo.com,2021-04-22:/blog/lessons-from-implementing-progression-frameworks-at-scale</id>
    <link href="https://monzo.com/blog/lessons-from-implementing-progression-frameworks-at-scale" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">We introduced the first progression framework for engineers about three years ago. But as the engineering organisation has changed, we found it was hurting, not helping career conversations at Monzo. This is what we did to fix it.</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>We&#39;re evolving engineering management at Monzo</title>
    <updated>2021-03-05T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>tag:monzo.com,2021-03-05:/blog/engineering-management-at-monzo-technical-leadership-people-support</id>
    <link href="https://monzo.com/blog/engineering-management-at-monzo-technical-leadership-people-support" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">We&#39;ve evolved our approach from supporting and developing individual engineers, to providing both excellent people support and technical leadership for teams and business areas.</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Autoscaling Monzo: How we optimise our platform to be just the right size</title>
    <updated>2020-10-19T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>tag:monzo.com,2020-10-19:/blog/2020/10/19/autoscaling-monzo</id>
    <link href="https://monzo.com/blog/2020/10/19/autoscaling-monzo" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">How we&#39;ve automated the process of scaling up our platform for our ever-growing userbase.</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>How we moved our Faster Payments connection in-house</title>
    <updated>2020-05-13T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>tag:monzo.com,2020-05-13:/blog/how-we-moved-our-faster-payments-connection-in-house</id>
    <link href="https://monzo.com/blog/how-we-moved-our-faster-payments-connection-in-house" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">Our in-house Faster Payments gateway has been running since November 2019. This is a comprehensive insight into how we built it.</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>How we&#39;ve evolved on-call at Monzo</title>
    <updated>2020-05-10T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>tag:monzo.com,2020-05-10:/blog/how-weve-evolved-on-call-at-monzo</id>
    <link href="https://monzo.com/blog/how-weve-evolved-on-call-at-monzo" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">We&#39;ve built a humane on-call rotation, that engineers actually want to join!</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Controlling outbound traffic from Kubernetes</title>
    <updated>2020-04-05T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>tag:monzo.com,2020-04-05:/blog/controlling-outbound-traffic-from-kubernetes</id>
    <link href="https://monzo.com/blog/controlling-outbound-traffic-from-kubernetes" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">We recently finished a major networking project which let us control internal traffic in our platform. And we&#39;ve been thinking about how we can add similar security to network traffic leaving our platform.</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>We migrated Vault&#39;s storage with no downtime</title>
    <updated>2019-12-17T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>tag:monzo.com,2019-12-17:/blog/migrating-vaults-storage-with-no-downtime</id>
    <link href="https://monzo.com/blog/migrating-vaults-storage-with-no-downtime" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">We use Vault for secret management and credential issuance, and we&#39;ve always configured it with the Cassandra storage backend. To help us scale, we moved to the S3 backend. But it was crucial we kept Vault available.</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>We secured thousands of Cassandra clients to keep Monzo&#39;s data safe</title>
    <updated>2019-12-17T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>tag:monzo.com,2019-12-17:/blog/we-secured-thousands-of-cassandra-clients-to-keep-monzos-data-safe</id>
    <link href="https://monzo.com/blog/we-secured-thousands-of-cassandra-clients-to-keep-monzos-data-safe" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">Our security team at Monzo are working towards a &#39;zero trust&#39; cluster, where an attacker inside our cluster would have no power.</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>We recently brought our Faster Payments connection in-house</title>
    <updated>2019-12-16T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>tag:monzo.com,2019-12-16:/blog/bringing-our-faster-payments-connection-in-house</id>
    <link href="https://monzo.com/blog/bringing-our-faster-payments-connection-in-house" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">It&#39;s been running smoothly, handling every single Faster Payment that you&#39;ve been sending in and out of Monzo!</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Coordinators on Android: how to build flows quickly with reusable screens</title>
    <updated>2019-12-12T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>tag:monzo.com,2019-12-12:/blog/coordinators-on-android-building-flows-quickly-with-reusable-screens</id>
    <link href="https://monzo.com/blog/coordinators-on-android-building-flows-quickly-with-reusable-screens" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">When we first built Monzo on Android, we couldn&#39;t &#39;reuse&#39; screens. We&#39;d build them from scratch every time! To help us work faster, we&#39;ve used a new architectural pattern called &#39;the Coordinator Pattern&#39; in our codebase.</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>We built network isolation for 1,500 services to make Monzo more secure</title>
    <updated>2019-11-06T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>tag:monzo.com,2019-11-06:/blog/we-built-network-isolation-for-1-500-services</id>
    <link href="https://monzo.com/blog/we-built-network-isolation-for-1-500-services" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">We&#39;ve been working on isolating the 1,500 services that power Monzo. The sheer size and complexity of our platform made this difficult. But by protecting us against compromised services, it makes Monzo more secure.</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>How our security team handle secrets</title>
    <updated>2019-10-11T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>tag:monzo.com,2019-10-11:/blog/2019/10/11/how-our-security-team-handle-secrets</id>
    <link href="https://monzo.com/blog/2019/10/11/how-our-security-team-handle-secrets" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">We recently designed a new system to manage secret information safely - from the keys that we use to sign your Mastercard transactions, to credentials for external services.</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>How we experiment at Monzo</title>
    <updated>2019-07-31T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>tag:monzo.com,2019-07-31:/blog/2019/07/31/how-we-experiment-at-monzo</id>
    <link href="https://monzo.com/blog/2019/07/31/how-we-experiment-at-monzo" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">Making big decisions is hard. So at Monzo, we test our ideas out whenever we can. Here&#39;s how that works!</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>How we respond to incidents</title>
    <updated>2019-07-08T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>tag:monzo.com,2019-07-08:/blog/2019/07/08/how-we-respond-to-incidents</id>
    <link href="https://monzo.com/blog/2019/07/08/how-we-respond-to-incidents" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">A good response process can mean the difference between something being resolved in minutes and an issue developing into something worse!</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>The role of technology in social inclusion</title>
    <updated>2019-07-03T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>tag:monzo.com,2019-07-03:/blog/2019/07/03/the-role-of-technology-in-social-inclusion</id>
    <link href="https://monzo.com/blog/2019/07/03/the-role-of-technology-in-social-inclusion" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">The technology we use to create Monzo can play a key part in our mission to make money work for everyone.</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>We&#39;re experiencing problems with some bank transfers</title>
    <updated>2019-05-30T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>tag:monzo.com,2019-05-30:/blog/2019/05/30/faster-payments-issue</id>
    <link href="https://monzo.com/blog/2019/05/30/faster-payments-issue" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">Some bank transfers aren&#39;t working. We&#39;re working on sorting it out asap.</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>How we accidentally broke our Android notification sounds (and fixed them!)</title>
    <updated>2019-05-28T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>tag:monzo.com,2019-05-28:/blog/2019/05/28/fixing-notifications-on-android</id>
    <link href="https://monzo.com/blog/2019/05/28/fixing-notifications-on-android" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">We encountered an interesting bug in our Android app notifications. Here&#39;s how we fixed it.</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>We deployed Envoy Proxy to make Monzo faster</title>
    <updated>2019-04-03T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>tag:monzo.com,2019-04-03:/blog/2019/04/03/deploying-envoy-proxy</id>
    <link href="https://monzo.com/blog/2019/04/03/deploying-envoy-proxy" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">We moved our remote procedure call (RPC) service mesh from Linkerd to Envoy to make Monzo faster.</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>How we improved our staff VPN</title>
    <updated>2019-03-19T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>tag:monzo.com,2019-03-19:/blog/2019/03/19/improving-our-staff-VPN</id>
    <link href="https://monzo.com/blog/2019/03/19/improving-our-staff-VPN" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">OpenVPN is great, but there were some things we wanted to change.</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>How we built Monzo Chat on Android</title>
    <updated>2019-02-11T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>tag:monzo.com,2019-02-11:/blog/2019/02/11/building-monzo-chat-on-android/</id>
    <link href="https://monzo.com/blog/2019/02/11/building-monzo-chat-on-android/" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">We&#39;ve built bespoke software from scratch, that helps us manage chats in the app. Here&#39;s how we implemented it on Android.</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>How we prepared our systems for our £20 million crowdfunding round</title>
    <updated>2019-01-16T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>tag:monzo.com,2019-01-16:/blog/2019/01/16/crowdfunding-technology-systems</id>
    <link href="https://monzo.com/blog/2019/01/16/crowdfunding-technology-systems" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">We prepared our systems for crowdfunding by shedding load, and built tools to help us monitor on the day.</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>How we load tested our bank before our £20 million crowdfunding round</title>
    <updated>2019-01-15T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>tag:monzo.com,2019-01-15:/blog/2019/01/15/crowdfunding-technology-testing</id>
    <link href="https://monzo.com/blog/2019/01/15/crowdfunding-technology-testing" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">More than 9,000 people opened their apps to invest in the first five minutes of crowdfunding. To make sure we were ready, we ran tests to simulate the extra load and upgraded our platform to cope with it.</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>How we built a backend for our £20 million crowdfunding round</title>
    <updated>2019-01-14T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>tag:monzo.com,2019-01-14:/blog/2019/01/14/crowdfunding-technology-backend-architecture</id>
    <link href="https://monzo.com/blog/2019/01/14/crowdfunding-technology-backend-architecture" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">We architected and built a scalable backend to support 36,000 investments.</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>The Refactathon: Cleaning up old code</title>
    <updated>2018-12-04T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>tag:monzo.com,2018-12-04:/blog/2018/11/29/refactoring-old-code</id>
    <link href="https://monzo.com/blog/2018/11/29/refactoring-old-code" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">We held an internal hackathon to improve some of the oldest code in the bank! Here&#39;s why that&#39;s good for our engineers and our customers.</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>How we do on-call at Monzo</title>
    <updated>2018-09-20T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>tag:monzo.com,2018-09-20:/blog/2018/09/20/on-call</id>
    <link href="https://monzo.com/blog/2018/09/20/on-call" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">A team of engineers are available 24/7/365 to respond when things go wrong. For other companies thinking about how to approach incidents, here&#39;s how we do on-call at Monzo.</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>How we monitor Monzo</title>
    <updated>2018-07-27T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>tag:monzo.com,2018-07-27:/blog/2018/07/27/how-we-monitor-monzo</id>
    <link href="https://monzo.com/blog/2018/07/27/how-we-monitor-monzo" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">We use tools to monitor all our systems to make sure everything&#39;s working as it should. Platform team lead Chris shares a technical insight into the way we monitor Monzo.</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>A technical look at how Monzo-to-Monzo payments work</title>
    <updated>2018-04-05T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>tag:monzo.com,2018-04-05:/blog/2018/04/05/how-monzo-to-monzo-payments-work</id>
    <link href="https://monzo.com/blog/2018/04/05/how-monzo-to-monzo-payments-work" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">Backend Engineer James Routley explains the technical work we do to help you send payments to your contacts on Monzo.</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>How We Build the Monzo App</title>
    <updated>2018-03-02T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>tag:monzo.com,2018-03-02:/blog/2018/03/02/app-development</id>
    <link href="https://monzo.com/blog/2018/03/02/app-development" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">Product Manager Jami explains how we turn a sneak peek on the forum into something you can hold in your hands.</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Very Robust etcd</title>
    <updated>2017-11-29T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>tag:monzo.com,2017-11-29:/blog/2017/11/29/very-robust-etcd</id>
    <link href="https://monzo.com/blog/2017/11/29/very-robust-etcd" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">We know Monzo&#39;s platform must be extremely reliable, and etcd is one of our most critical components. We&#39;ve gone to great lengths to make sure it can survive a range of failures.</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Working with backend services on iOS</title>
    <updated>2017-07-07T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>tag:monzo.com,2017-07-07:/blog/2017/07/07/working-with-backend-services-on-ios</id>
    <link href="https://monzo.com/blog/2017/07/07/working-with-backend-services-on-ios" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">How we refactored our iOS app to work better with backend services.</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Terminal decline: Why some payments fail</title>
    <updated>2017-05-05T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>tag:monzo.com,2017-05-05:/blog/2017/05/05/why-payments-are-declined</id>
    <link href="https://monzo.com/blog/2017/05/05/why-payments-are-declined" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">We break down the common causes of declined card payments.</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Practical Machine Learning With Event Streaming</title>
    <updated>2017-05-03T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>tag:monzo.com,2017-05-03:/blog/2017/05/03/practical-machine-learning-for-startups</id>
    <link href="https://monzo.com/blog/2017/05/03/practical-machine-learning-for-startups" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">Monzo&#39;s Head of Data and Analytics walks through our recent advances in using machine learning to make predictions based on existing data.</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>4 useful services your bank should not be charging you for</title>
    <updated>2017-02-17T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>tag:monzo.com,2017-02-17:/blog/2017/02/17/four-useful-services-your-bank-should-not-be-charging-for</id>
    <link href="https://monzo.com/blog/2017/02/17/four-useful-services-your-bank-should-not-be-charging-for" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">Click to read more</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>5 Features Your Mobile Bank Account Should Have By Now</title>
    <updated>2017-02-13T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>tag:monzo.com,2017-02-13:/blog/2017/02/13/5-features-your-mobile-bank-account-should-have-by-now</id>
    <link href="https://monzo.com/blog/2017/02/13/5-features-your-mobile-bank-account-should-have-by-now" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">Click to read more</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Fighting Fraud with Machine Learning</title>
    <updated>2017-02-03T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>tag:monzo.com,2017-02-03:/blog/2017/02/03/fighting-fraud-with-machine-learning</id>
    <link href="https://monzo.com/blog/2017/02/03/fighting-fraud-with-machine-learning" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">How we have prevented £400,000 of fraud over the last 6 months</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Designing a product with mental health issues in mind</title>
    <updated>2017-01-27T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>tag:monzo.com,2017-01-27:/blog/2017/01/27/designing-product-mental-health-mind</id>
    <link href="https://monzo.com/blog/2017/01/27/designing-product-mental-health-mind" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">How we&#39;re designing Monzo to be a powerful and unique financial service for our most vulnerable customers.</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Laying the foundation for a data team</title>
    <updated>2016-11-29T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>tag:monzo.com,2016-11-29:/blog/2016/11/30/laying-the-foundation-for-a-data-team</id>
    <link href="https://monzo.com/blog/2016/11/30/laying-the-foundation-for-a-data-team" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">At Monzo, we want to build the best bank account in the world. Today, more than ever before, data is central to creating wonderful customer experiences and efficient internal operations.</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Building a Modern Bank Backend</title>
    <updated>2016-09-19T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>tag:monzo.com,2016-09-19:/blog/2016/09/19/building-a-modern-bank-backend</id>
    <link href="https://monzo.com/blog/2016/09/19/building-a-modern-bank-backend" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">This first post in a series about our platform explains how we&#39;re building systems to meet these demands using modern, open-source technology...</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>