<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Monzo US</title>
    <link>https://monzo.com/us/blog</link>
    <description>An unofficial Monzo US blog feed generated by Akash Goswami (https://akashgoswami.dev)</description>
    <pubDate>Fri, 16 May 2025 01:30:10 +0000</pubDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/skyth3r/monzo-blog-feed/refs/heads/main/icon.svg</url>
      <title>Monzo</title>
      <link>https://monzo.com/us/blog</link>
    </image>
    <item>
      <title>You can now earn up to 4.25% APY on your money with Monzo Savings Jars</title>
      <link>https://monzo.com/us/blog/monzo-us-blog/monzo-savings-jars-launch</link>
      <description>Today marks an exciting step on the Monzo journey, as we announce interest on Savings Jars. You&#39;ll now be able to earn interest on money saved in your Jars.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What is APY?</title>
      <link>https://monzo.com/us/blog/what-is-apy</link>
      <description>If you&#39;re new to saving, you might be wondering what APY is and why it&#39;s so important. Here&#39;s the lowdown…</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Achieve your savings goals on time with Pots</title>
      <link>https://monzo.com/us/blog/monzo-us-blog/pot-goals</link>
      <description>Set up a savings goal with a date on a Pot, and we&#39;ll help you work out what you need to save to reach your goal.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cover your expenses by paying directly from Pots</title>
      <link>https://monzo.com/us/blog/monzo-us-blog/pay-from-pots</link>
      <description>Pots help you set aside enough money for the important things. And now you can pay from them. It&#39;s envelope budgeting, made digital.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>There&#39;s no place like Home</title>
      <link>https://monzo.com/us/blog/monzo-us-blog/new-home-screen</link>
      <description>Get to know the new Monzo app Home screen, made for better visibility and control of your finances.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How I use Monzo Pots for cash stuffing</title>
      <link>https://monzo.com/us/blog/monzo-us-blog/pots-envelope-budget</link>
      <description>Melanie*, 25, uses Pots for her budget using the envelope budget method, also called cash stuffing. Here&#39;s how she organizes her budget for the month.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Spend confidently with category targets</title>
      <link>https://monzo.com/us/blog/monzo-us-blog/trends-category-targets</link>
      <description>Whether you&#39;re a budgeting novice or looking for a more streamlined approach, category targets help you stay on track with your finances and budget.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Salary Sorter - the simple solution to make the most of your paycheck </title>
      <link>https://monzo.com/us/blog/monzo-us-blog/auto-salary-sorter</link>
      <description>Sort your paycheck automatically so it&#39;s neatly organized into Pots for you as soon as you get paid.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Stay ahead of credit card debt with a Credit Card Pot</title>
      <link>https://monzo.com/us/blog/monzo-us-blog/credit-card-pot</link>
      <description>Automatically set aside a little bit of your money when you use your credit card. Whatever is saved will help pay off your balance.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Plan for the unexpected with an emergency fund Pot</title>
      <link>https://monzo.com/us/blog/monzo-us-blog/emergency-fund-pot</link>
      <description>Don&#39;t get caught in the rain: our new emergency fund Pots have you covered for unexpected expenses and whatever else life pours on you.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The perks of having a joint account with Monzo</title>
      <link>https://monzo.com/us/blog/monzo-us-blog/joint-account-perks</link>
      <description>A joint account can make it easier for two people to manage their shared finances together, like everyday spending or household bills.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Managing money together: how to get started with your Monzo joint account</title>
      <link>https://monzo.com/us/blog/monzo-us-blog/joint-accounts-get-started</link>
      <description>A joint account can make it easier for two people to manage their shared finances together. Here&#39;s how to get started with a joint account at Monzo.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Get paid early with faster direct deposit</title>
      <link>https://monzo.com/us/blog/monzo-us-blog/get-paid-early</link>
      <description>Get paid up to 2 days early when you set up direct deposit with Monzo.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Help us test joint accounts</title>
      <link>https://monzo.com/us/blog/monzo-us-blog/joint-accounts-beta</link>
      <description>A joint account is a shared account between two people, making it easy to pay bills or save for goals together. Help us beta test today!</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Introducing Trends - the future of money management</title>
      <link>https://monzo.com/us/blog/monzo-us-blog/trends</link>
      <description>Trends is designed to give you even more visibility of your entire financial life with just a tap. See a breakdown of your spending and saving across all your Monzo and external connected accounts together.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tipping made easy</title>
      <link>https://monzo.com/us/blog/monzo-us-blog/tip-tracker</link>
      <description>Tracking your tips with Monzo will show your updated balance immediately while the final amount is being processed. Our built-in tip calculator even does the math for you!</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My first 6 months as an Android Engineer and Backend Engineer at Monzo</title>
      <link>https://monzo.com/us/blog/monzo-us-blog/first-six-months-android-engineer-backend-engineer</link>
      <description>Ryan joined Monzo as the first Android Engineer on the US team and has also done some work as a Backend Engineer. Read about why he joined Monzo!</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Manage your money and get visibility across multiple bank accounts</title>
      <link>https://monzo.com/us/blog/monzo-us-blog/manage-multiple-bank-accounts</link>
      <description>Track your spending, balances, and more all in the Monzo app when you connect your external bank accounts and credit cards.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Supporting mental health and wellbeing at Monzo</title>
      <link>https://monzo.com/us/blog/monzo-us-blog/supporting-mental-health-and-wellbeing</link>
      <description>At Monzo, mental health is just as important as physical health. These are a few things we&#39;ve done to support mental health and wellbeing.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Interviewing at Monzo: an overview of our interview process</title>
      <link>https://monzo.com/us/blog/monzo-us-blog/interviewing-at-monzo</link>
      <description>At Monzo, we hire for strengths and our interview process is designed to learn about those strengths.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Who are our users: 2022 survey insights</title>
      <link>https://monzo.com/us/blog/2022/04/05/monzo-us-blog-2022-survey-insights</link>
      <description>We sent out a survey to thousands of US users to get an idea of what to build next, but wanted to share some of the most interesting points we saw.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Monzo is working to build a more empathetic workplace</title>
      <link>https://monzo.com/us/blog/monzo-us-blog/working-to-build-more-empathetic-workplace</link>
      <description>As we continue to build an amazing team and product in the US, we want to share a few ways in which Monzo helps create a more empathetic workplace.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Monzo Moves from Beta to Public Launch in the US!</title>
      <link>https://monzo.com/us/blog/2022/02/01/monzo-us-blog-monzo-moves-from-beta-to-public-launch-in-the-us</link>
      <description>Today, Monzo is moving out of closed beta and opening Monzo to customers across America! The wait(list) is over - if you want a Monzo account, just download the app and apply.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New Year, New Budget</title>
      <link>https://monzo.com/us/blog/monzo-us-blog/new-year-new-budget</link>
      <description>2022 is just around the corner, so it&#39;s the perfect time to set some New Year&#39;s resolutions, get your finances in order, and make a plan for the year ahead.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>October Virtual Community Event Recap</title>
      <link>https://monzo.com/us/blog/2021/11/15/monzo-us-blog-october-virtual-community-event-recap</link>
      <description>The Monzo US team recently held our second virtual community meetup. We were super excited to share the progress from the past six months, as well as meet and answer questions from many of our passionate users!</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Meet Nathan, our Head of Engineering</title>
      <link>https://monzo.com/us/blog/2021/11/11/monzo-us-blog-meet-nathan-our-head-of-engineering</link>
      <description>In the third installment of our “Meet the Monzo US Team”, we talk to Nathan Woo, our new Head of Engineering.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Scheduled payments, made easy</title>
      <link>https://monzo.com/us/blog/monzo-us-blog/scheduled-payments</link>
      <description>You can now see all your scheduled and recurring payments in one place within the Payments tab of your Monzo app.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Introducing Salary Sorter</title>
      <link>https://monzo.com/us/blog/monzo-us-blog/salary-sorter</link>
      <description>When you get paid into Monzo, our new Salary Sorter gives you the option to automatically divide up incoming payments into different pots, with the rest left in your main balance to spend.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Move money to and from your other accounts - now in Beta testing</title>
      <link>https://monzo.com/us/blog/2021/08/24/monzo-us-blog-move-money-to-and-from-your-other-accounts-now-in-beta-testing</link>
      <description>From today you&#39;ll be able to link your other non-Monzo accounts to your Monzo account. Quickly add money to your Monzo account from linked accounts, or move money from Monzo to any of your other accounts - all from inside the Monzo app.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Meet Richard, a Monzo US Backend Engineer</title>
      <link>https://monzo.com/us/blog/2021/07/19/meet-richard-a-monzo-us-backend-engineer</link>
      <description>In the first of our “Meet the Monzo US Team” series of blog posts, we talk to Richard Dingwall, one of our superstar engineers who has been with Monzo for over 5 years and who has been working on the US team for the past year and a half.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Updating our Product Roadmap for 2021</title>
      <link>https://monzo.com/us/blog/2021/05/18/monzo-us-blog-updating-our-product-roadmap-for-2021</link>
      <description>We&#39;ve excited to share with you our updated product roadmap. Since we shared our public roadmap in January 2020 a lot has changed, and so we felt like the time was now right to update our product roadmap and share this with our community. </description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Personalized Cards Have Landed</title>
      <link>https://monzo.com/us/blog/2020/12/16/monzo-us-blog-personalized-cards-have-landed</link>
      <description>We&#39;re excited to announce that we&#39;ve rolled out our newly designed, personalized Monzo USA cards. You can now order a card with your name on it - no more awkwardly being called “Monzo Beta” when picking up a coffee at your local shop!</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>You can now hide your Monzo US Pots and change the order they&#39;re in!</title>
      <link>https://monzo.com/us/blog/2020/05/15/monzo-us-blog-you-can-now-hide-your-pots-and-change-the-order-theyre-in-us</link>
      <description>See what&#39;s important to you first, and hide Pots you don&#39;t want to see every day.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Monzo US: We&#39;re here to support you with your money and your Monzo account during the coronavirus outbreak</title>
      <link>https://monzo.com/us/blog/2020/03/18/monzo-us-blog-coronavirus-update</link>
      <description>If you are affected by coronavirus, it could also impact your income, your finances, and how you&#39;re able to manage your money. That&#39;s why we want to reassure you that we&#39;re well-equipped to support you and keep Monzo running</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>US Beta Update 🔧</title>
      <link>https://monzo.com/us/blog/2020/03/11/monzo-us-blog-us-update-waitlist</link>
      <description>You can now move up the Monzo waitlist faster 🚀</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Introducing our transparent product roadmap - US</title>
      <link>https://monzo.com/us/blog/24/01/2020/monzo-us-blog-us-product-roadmap</link>
      <description>We&#39;re excited to say that we&#39;re slowly starting to offer Monzo accounts to those on our US waitlist! 🚀</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Contactless cards  </title>
      <link>https://monzo.com/us/blog/2020/01/14/monzo-us-blog-contactless</link>
      <description>All Monzo Beta cards are now contactless, so you can tap to pay 🙌</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pots are here on Monzo Beta!</title>
      <link>https://monzo.com/us/blog/2020/01/15/monzo-us-blog-pots-us-beta</link>
      <description>Pots on Monzo are a way to help you budget and save for your goals 🍯</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Monzo is launching in the USA!</title>
      <link>https://monzo.com/us/blog/2019/06/13/monzo-us-blog-monzo-usa</link>
      <description>Our mission is to make money work for everyone. And our next stop is the USA! 🇺🇸</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>